and survival was a daily adventure.
Get ready to be amazed.
Forget the image of cavemen hitting rocks together.
Stone Age tools evolved dramatically over millions of years.
From simple choppers to finally, crafted hand axes, the ingenuity of our ancestors will
stand you.
Homo have a leaves, Homo recticych species left a unique mark in the technological landscape
using tools to hunt mammoths, carve wood, and shape their wealth.
And yes, they even cooked their food using fire.
The Stone Age wasn't just about hunting and gathering.
Around 12,000 years ago, something incredible happened, the neolithic revolution.
Humans learned to farm, leading to settled villages, the domestication of animals like sheep
and goats, and the creation of the first pottery and woven fabrics.
Suddenly, life was less about constant wandering and more about building-masting communities
and cultivating the land-atoning point in human history.
Think the Stone Age was all about bare necessities.
Think again.
Cave paintings, intricate carvings, and even personal adornment show rich symbolic life,
suggesting complex thought and belief systems.
From cave paintings, the painting animals to the earliest forms of burial rituals,
the evidence of creativity and spiritual expression is undeniable.
It paints a vibrant picture of the human spirit far beyond simply surviving.
The Stone Age eventually gave way to the bronze on nine ages as human's massive metallurgy.
But even today, the legacy of the Stone Age remains profound.
It's the foundation upon which all of human civilization is built.
So hit that like button if you learned something new and smash that subscribe button for
more mind-blowing historical genus.
Don't forget to share this video with your friends.