The USA is the largest and most influential economy to have ever existed in human history.
For over a century, it has dominated the world.
More wealth has been credited here in just the last 20 years and the entire world
credit between 1 and 1,700 IED.
But the question is, why?
Capital moved faster.
Once you get a dominant position in the currency, it's very difficult to lose it.
Immigration and innovation.
The US financial markets are the deepest, broadest, biggest markets in the world.
I haven't yet to meet a person on Wall Street who can operate on somebody's brain.
The economics-explaning team traveled across the world to try and answer this one simple question.
We sat down with some of the brightest minds in economics, finance and policy to find out.
I came to Wall Street because I had no money growing up as a kid and I wanted to get rich.
The USA isn't the largest country in the world.
It doesn't have the most resources or the most manpower.
So what was it's secret?
The wealth has been concentrated with a very small percentage.
The United States is able to allocate resources in a way which gives the United States a significant advantage.
This is a culture of risk takers.
One of the reasons that the US has stronger trend growth, we allow more migrants in.
Does this all work when the US has to share the global spotlight with arrival?
And what happens if the American Empire stops working for the American people?
The United States is able to work for the American people.